Alexander Musayev

Date of birth: 17 Jul 1981 E-mail/jabber: alex.musayev@gmail.com

Location: Saint-Petersburg, Russia Skype: dreikanter

Education: Higher technical Phone: +7 (905) 266-61-66

Skills and specialization

Nine years of experience in software design and development. Requirements analysis, system design, tasks decomposition and estimation, specifications and technical documentation development. UI/UX design and prototyping. Keeping things in order and transforming the Complex into the Simple.

• Primary programming languages:

- **C#** (.net 1.1-4.0, winforms/wpf, wcf, spring.net, moq, xunit, nunit, wix, msmq, zeromq, log4net, nlog, 3rd party UI components).
- o **Python** 2.6-3.3 (django, web.py, jinja2, argparse, logging, unit tests, etc).
- Minor experience in JavaScript and Ruby.
- Databases: mysql, sqlite, microsoft sql server (std, express, ce), mongo, redis.
- **Web-related:** html, css, less, twitter bootstrap and some other web frameworks. Servers: apache, nginx.
- **Version control:** git is the personal preference; also has experience with svn, p4, tfs.
- **IDE and favorite tools:** microsoft visual studio since 6.0, jetbrains pycharm, sublime text, visio, linux shell, photoshop.
- English and Russian languages.

Interests

Product development, analysis, distributed systems architecture, web technologies, UI/UX design.

Experience

Senior software developer (Outsourcing)

Luxoft, Saint-Petersburg (http://luxoft.com) Jan 2012 — Present time

Participated in enterprise-grade projects development (HP, Modular Mining). New features development and existing codebase support. Technical interviews conduction.

Last update: 28.09.2013 21:20

Software developer (Outsourcing, R&D)

Lanit-Tercom, Saint-Petersburg (http://lanit-tercom.ru)
Aug 2008 — Dec 2011

Responsibility:

- Enterprise software development (desktop applications and web services), testing, deployment and support (.NET/C#, PL/SQL, Java, Flex).
- Requirements analysis, tasks decomposition and estimation, creating specifications and project documentation.
- UI prototyping and development, UI logic formalization.

Achievements:

- Analytical information system for thermal power plants for Infoenergo Ltd. (Russia).
- Web-based media management system for DTS Medien AG (Germany).
- Medical data management system for Huntington Hospital (California, USA) / dbMotion Ltd. (Israel).

Software developer (R&D)

SZMA LLC, Saint-Petersburg (http://szma.com)
Aug 2006 — Dec 2009

Responsibility:

- Architecture design for distributed software.
- Requirements analysis, specification drafting and project documentation.
- Software development, testing, deployment and support (C#, Matlab, MQL, MySQL, PHP).
- Technical documentation and user manuals drafting.

Achievements:

- Web service for financial data collection, verification, and analysis.
- Middleware for Matlab integration with Metaquotes MetaTrader (trading platform).

Post graduate student

SPIIRAS, Saint-Petersburg (http://spiiras.nw.ru) Dec 2004 — Dec 2008

Responsibility:

- Research in the field of mathematical modeling, scientific conferences participation.
- Participating in development of Computer-aided Modeling System for the Large-scale Social Economic Projects (Russian Foundation for Basic Research grant).
- Experimental software development (C#).
- Training course development for third-year university students.

Achievements:

• A number of publications in science magazines and institute proceedings on mathematical modeling and enterprise automation.

Professor assistant

SPb UWC, Saint-Petersburg (http://spbuwc.ru)
Oct 2006 — Jul 2008

Responsibility:

- Training course development for university students.
- Lecturing and running workshops on C++ programming, seminars organization on enterprise software development.
- Exams admission, participating in the examination committee for the "Information Security" specialty.

Achievements:

- Practical programming experience in high-level languages for about 50 university students.
- Lecture notes on C++ programming.

Software developer

7+11 Company Ltd., Saint-Petersburg (http://7plus11.ru)
Jul 2003 — Oct 2007

Responsibility:

- Distributed systems design and developing for enterprise automation and monitoring systems.
- Data collection and visualization systems development.
- Embedded software testing, deployment and support.
- Requirements analysis, technical documentation.
- Office LAN administration (25 workplaces).

Achievements:

- Launched automated control systems for VTB Bank headquarters, Kronverk Business Center and a number of other office and residential buildings in Saint-Petersburg.
- Kilowatt-hours and gigacalories saved by control algorithms optimization for embedded systems.

Last update: 28.09.2013 21:20

Some of personal open source projects

- Bibliography generator for science texts based on the GOST 7.0.5-2008 standard requirements (a tool which helps to get rid of a cumbersome list of weak rules which should be kept in mind during bibliography drafting).
- Google Chrome browser extensions with a few thousands of users.
- Automation tools, content management systems, Wordpress plug-ins, python libraries for text processing, etc.

Most of the listed projects are hosted on GitHub: http://github.com/dreikanter.

Education

Higher: St. Petersburg State University of Airspace Instrumentation (SUAI)

Department of Automatic Control Systems

Specialty: Automatic Control and Information Processing Systems

1998 - 2004

Postgraduate: St. Petersburg Institute for Informatics and Automation of Russian

Academy of Sciences (SPIIRAS)

Specialty: Mathematical and Software Support of Computers,

Complex Systems and Networks

2004 - 2008

Trainings/certificates

• Brainbench certificates: C, HTML.

- Careerlab certificate: High Level Architecture Design with UML.
- System Analysis School certificate for software requirements development course.
- Few other course completion certificates on system analysis and software architecture.
- Artyom Gorbunov's Educational Center certificate: User Experience design and Information Visualization.

Miscellaneous

- Traveling passport is available, Inland and abroad business trips experience.
- U.S. visa.

Last update: 28.09.2013 21:20